Mobile: 07411252642

Email: rmatias12@outlook.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/rematias GitHub: github.com/RenataMatias

Visa: Work Permitted (No sponsorship required)

Glasgow, UK

# **Renata Cardoso Matias**

#### Qualification Profile

A highly focused, resourceful, and enthusiastic Engineer turning into a Front End Developer, with knowledge of HTML, CSS JavaScript and React. Skilled in building and maintaining responsive websites. With 9 years of experience in Subsea Engineering, possess strong skills in numerical, analytical, and problem-solving, with adaptable, fast learner and a good team player. Creative mindset, intellectually curious, and able to rapidly pick up new-to-you concepts and solve complex puzzles. Aspiring to gain entry and start the next challenging career in a tech-oriented environment, where I can learn new expertise and expand my skills-set. Solid commitment to explore new emerging technologies and drive career growth. Speaks Portuguese and English.

#### **Core Skills**

- Front End Development
- Programming Languages
- Analytical & Critical Thinker
- HTML, CSS
- JavaScript, React
- Scrum Principles & Practices
- Creative & Adaptable
- Problem Resolution

#### **Education & Credentials**

Front End Development: SheCodes, 2022 - 2022

React Development, Responsive Web Development, Web Development

BEng in Mechanical Engineering: Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro (UFRJ), 2008 – 2014

English Language Course: ELC Australia, 2012 – 2012

### **Additional Qualifications**

Scrum – Principles and Practices: EDTI, 2021

Figma: Cursae, 2020
Data Science: 365 Careers, 2020
Lean Six-Sigma Green Belt: EDTI, 2020

IT Proficiencies: React, JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, API, GitHub, Hosting, Flexbox, Responsive, SEO

## **Career Experience**

#### Cancer Research UK – United Kingdom

Feb 2022 to Present

#### **Shop Volunteer**

Serve the general public, process payments, and provide good all-around customer service. Organise and classify stock of donated items. Merchandise stock in visually appealing and arrange displays for representing products in a better way.

TechnipFMC – Brazil June 2013 to Jan 2022

#### **Subsea Installation Analysis Engineer**

Aug 2019 to Jan 2022

Conducted installation analysis of Flexible Pipes, Umbilicals, and Subsea Equipments for TechinpFMC's PLSV ships (Pipe Laying Support Vessels) using Orcaflex Software to validate the strength capacity. Coordinated with other engineers to ensure that designs meet all applicable standards and regulations.

- Evaluated the installation feasibility of new products (flexible pipes) made by TechinpFMC through analysis.
- Ensured that work performed met quality standards as well as regulatory requirements.
- Reviewed progress on each task and identified any potential issues early on to mitigate risk.

#### **Subsea Project Engineer**

May 2014 to Aug 2019

Served as an engineer and led subsea projects for the installation and recovery of Flexible Pipes, Umbilicals, and Subsea Equipments by PLSV ships. Coordinated directly with the client to ensure project alignment and discuss the proposals for solutions in projects. Responsible for conducting feasibility and risk analysis of the projects, as well as the preparation of operational diagrams and schedules. Prepared technical evaluation of contracts before it is signed with the client.

- Developed all operational procedures and projects documentations and interpreted drawings to meet specifications.
- Analysed processes during the installation/recovery projects and implemented best practices and solutions.
- Reviewed project progress and liaised frequently with the Ship's Crew, Product Design team (flexible pipes design),
  Installation Analysis teams (Orcaflex), and Accessories teams (new vessel's modifications) to ensure project
  success.
- Developed strong technical capabilities by coordinating with different teams: PLSV Skandi Recife, PLSV Skandi Olinda, PLSV Skandi Niteroi, PLSV Skandi Vitoria, PLSV 55ot TOP Estrela do Mar, PLSV 55ot TOP Coral do Atlântico, PLSV 65ot Skandi Acu and PLSV 65ot Skandi Búzios.
- Created and revised vessels' equipment manuals as well as supervised the commissioning process of new systems before handing them over to clients for use.

#### Internship - Subsea Projects

Jan 2014 to May 2014

Acted as an active member of the team and directly responsible for the construction phase and pre-operation of PLSV 55ot TOP Estrela do Mar and TOP Coral do Atlântico.

- Reviewed and updated the inventories of the vessels, necessary for the vessels' entry into the country.
- Elaborated the MTO's relation of everything that was bought along the construction of the vessels.
- Studied and evaluated the PLSV's methods of loading, installation, and recovery of flexible pipes for future projects.

Purchaser - Procurement June 2013 to Jan 2014

Researched, identified, and developed new suppliers and negotiated pricing to achieve cost savings. Consistently maintained the budgetary requirements as well as met deadlines and delivery service.

- Chased suppliers and assisted in the preparation of comparatives of budgets through Corporate Quotation Maps and issuance of Purchase Orders (PO) in the Oracle system.
- Supported various projects, including Flexibras Port of Açu, Ubarana, and improvements to Port of Angra dos Reis.

#### VARD Shipyard – Brazil

Oct 2012 to Jan 2013

#### Internship - Engineering

Supported the project team on the construction of the ship PRO 30. Assisted the team in preparing and translating the ship's manuals. Re-checked hydraulic diagrams.

#### COPPE/ Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro (UFRJ) – Brazil

Feb 2011 to Dec 2011

#### Internship - Engineering

Worked with acquisition of mioelectric signals (electric current from human muscular contractions) through electrodes in the Acoustic and Vibrations Laboratory, analysing and treating signals and data in LabView software to control a mechanical arm.

## **Networks & Memberships**

Engineers Ireland – Dublin (Membership Number: 486467)

#### **Interests**

Meditation; yoga; travel with friends and family; learn new things

#### References

References and certificates available upon request.